Switchmen's Union of North America Additional Unification Minutes and Convention Proceedings 5447
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Switchmen's Union of North America Additional Unification Minutes and Convention Proceedings
1908-1971
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Switchmen's Union of North America (SUNA)
5447
7 cubic feet
7 linear ft.
Records (documents), minutes (administrative records).
Unification minutes, convention proceedings, and other files of the Switchmen's Union of North America.
5649181
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183 kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, March 11, 2014
EAD encoding:
Kheel Staff, March 13, 2019
Biographical / Historical
The Switchmen's Union of North America is among the older of the railway brotherhoods. Beginning in 1877 with the formation of a local Switchmen's organization in Chicago, the movement became national when the Switchmen's Mutual Aid Association of North America held its first meeting nine years later.
This association was destroyed, as a result of a disastrous lockout by the Chicago Northwestern and the 1888 strike against the Chicago, Burlington and Quincy which had equally unfortunate results. Building on what was left of the S.M.A.A., several lodges met in Kansas City in October of 1854 and formed the Switchmen's Union of North America.
By the time of its merger into the United Transportation Union in 1969, the single Chicago labor organization of 1877 had grown to international status with 275 lodges in the United States and Canada having a combined membership of 12,000.
Scope and Contents
Unification minutes, convention proceedings, and other files of the Switchmen's Union of North America.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: 5034: Switchmen's Union of North America Records 5034 MB: Switchmen's Union of North America Memorabilia 5034 P: Switchmen's Union of North America Photographs 5084: Switchmen's Union of North America Additional Records 5405 mf: Switchmen's Union of North America Constitutions on Microfilm 5406 mf: Switchmen's Union of North America Arbitration on Microfilm 5556: Switchmen's Union of North America Additional Records 5556 AV: Switchmen's Union of North America Audio-Visual Materials 5590: Switchmen's Union of North America Lake Shore Lodge 55 Membership Registers 5613: Switchmen's Union of North America Oakland Lodge 158 Meeting Minutes 5630: W.B. Meyers Papers
Railroads -- Employees -- Labor unions -- United States.; Railroads -- United States.; Switchmen's Union of North America
5649181
- Rituals of the Switchmen's Union., 1935 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  Scope and Contents
  4 booklets.
- Ritual Booklets (3), 1944 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Rituals of the Switchmen's Union., 1963 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  2 booklets.
- Constitution and By-laws, 1930-1941 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  4 booklets
- Constitution and By-Laws, 1947-1951 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Constitution and By-Laws, 1963-1967 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Constitution and By-Laws. Ladies' Auxiliary., 1947 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Constitution and By-Laws: Omaha Railway Employees Benefit Association., 1952 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Directories., 1952 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Directories of the Switchmen's Union., 1953 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Directories of the Switchmen's Union., 1954 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  6 booklets
- Directories of the Switchmen's Union., 1955 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  3 booklets.
- Directories of the Switchmen's Union., 1956 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  6 booklets.
- Directories of the Switchmen's Union., 1957 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  5 booklets.
- Directories of the Switchmen's Union., 1958 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Directories of the Switchmen's Union., 1959 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Directories of the Switchmen's Union., 1960 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  1 booklet.
- Directories of the Switchmen's Union., 1961 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Directories of the Switchmen's Union., 1962 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Directories of the Switchmen's Union., 1963 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Directories of the Switchmen's Union., 1964 (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Directories of the Switchmen's Union., 1965 (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Directories of the Switchmen's Union., 1966 (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Directories of the Switchmen's Union., 1967 (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Directories of the Switchmen's Union., 1968 (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Report of the Committee of General Managers., 1909 (Box 1, Folder 26)
- Minutes of the Special Conference of the Railways., 1916 (Box 1, Folder 27)
- Chief Executives Meeting., 1920 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  August 13 1920
- Report of the Committee on the Constitution., 1927 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  Bound notebook.
- Fifth National Session of SUNA., 1900 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  May 1900.
- Convention. The 21st Session of SUNA. Transcript., 1941 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  June 9 1941. Pages 1 - 106.
- Convention. The 21st Session of SUNA. Transcript., 1941 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  June 10 - 11 1941. Pages 107 - 213.
- Convention. The 21st Session of SUNA. Transcript., 1941 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  June 12 1941. Pages 214 - 319.
- Convention. The 21st Session of SUNA. Transcript., 1941 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  June 13 1941. Pages 320 - 384.
- Convention 22nd Session. Transcript., 1947 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  June 9 - 10 1947. Pages 1 - 108.
- Convention 22nd Session. Transcript., 1947 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  June 11 - 12 1947. Pages 109 - 279.
- Convention 22nd Session. Transcript., 1947 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  June 13 1947. Pages 280 - 458.
- Convention 22nd Session. Transcript., 1947 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  June 14 - 16 1947. Pages 459 - 556.
- Convention 22nd Session. Transcript., 1947 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  June 9 - 10 1947. Pages 1 - 108. Copy 2.
- Convention 22nd Session. Transcript., 1947 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  June 11 - 12 1947. Pages 109 - 279. Copy 2.
- Convention 22nd Session. Transcript., 1947 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  June 13 1947. Pages 280 - 458. Copy 2.
- Convention 22nd Session. Transcript., 1947 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  June 14 - 16 1947. Pages 459 - 556. Copy 2.
- Convention 22nd Session. Booklets., 1947 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Convention 23rd Session. Transcript., 1951 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  June 11 1951. Pages 1 - 111.
- Convention 23rd Session. Transcript., 1951 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  June 12 1951. Pages 112 - 305.
- Convention 23rd Session. Transcript., 1951 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  June 13 - 15 1951. Pages 306 - 443.
- Convention 23rd Session. Transcript., 1951 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  June 15 1951. Pages 444 - 638.
- Convention 23rd Session. Transcript., 1957 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  June 16 1957. Pages 639 - 792.
- Convention 23rd Session. Transcript., 1951 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  June 17 - 18 1951. Pages 793 - 911.
- Convention 23rd Session. Transcript., 1951 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  Officer's Report Booklet.
- Special Convention. Transcript., 1953 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  April 27 1953. Pages 1 - 144.
- Special Convention. Transcript., 1953 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  April 28 1953. Pages 145 - 371.
- Special Convention. Transcript., 1953 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  April 29 1953. Pages 372 - 715.
- Special Convention. Transcript., 1953 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  April 30 1953. Pages 716 - 923.
- Special Convention. Transcript., 1953 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  May 1 1953. Pages 924 - 1041.
- Convention 24th Session. Transcript., 1955 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  June 13 - 14 1955. Pages 1 - 194.
- Convention 24th Session. Transcript., 1955 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  June 15 1955. Pages 195 - 317.
- Convention 24th Session. Transcript., 1955 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  June 16 1955. Pages 318 - 440.
- Convention 24th Session. Transcript., 1955 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  June 17 1955. Pages 441 - 553.
- Convention 24th Session. Transcript., 1955 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  June 18 1955. Pages 554 - 650.
- Convention 24th Session. Transcript., 1955 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  June 20 - 21 1955. Pages 651 - 849.
- Convention 24th Session. Booklets., 1955 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  2 Booklets.
- Convention 25th Session. Transcript., 1959 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  June 8 1959.
- Convention 25th Session. Transcript., 1959 (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Convention 25th Session. Transcript., 1959 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  June 10 1959.
- Convention 25th Session. Transcript., 1959 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  June 11 1959.
- Convention 25th Session. Transcript., 1959 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  Morning. June 12 1959.
- Convention 25th Session. Transcript., 1959 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  Afternoon. June 12 1959
- Convention 25th Session. Transcript., 1959 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  June 15 1959. Booklet.
- Convention 26th Session. Transcript., 1963 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  July 17 1963. Pages 1 - 187.
- Convention 26th Session. Transcript., 1963 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  June 18 1963. Pages 188 - 353.
- Convention 26th Session. Transcript., 1963 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  June 19 - 20 1963. Pages 354 - 542.
- Convention 26th Session. Booklets., 1963 (Box 3, Folder 17)
- Convention 27th Session. Transcript., 1967 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  July 10 1967. Pages 1 - 186.
- Convention 27th Session. Transcript., 1967 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  July 11 1967. Pages 187 - 407.
- Convention 27th Session. Transcript., 1967 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  July 12 1967. Pages 408 - 610.
- Convention 27th Session. Transcript., 1967 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  July 13 1967. Pages 611 - 857.
- Convention 27th Session. Transcript., 1967 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  July 14 1967. Pages 858 - 1154.
- Convention 27th Session. Transcript., 1967 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  July 15 1967. Pages 1155 - 1361.
- Convention 27th Session. Transcript., 1967 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  July 10 1967. Pages 1 - 186. Copy 2.
- Convention 27th Session. Transcript., 1967 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  July 11 1967. Pages 187 - 407. Copy 2.
- Convention 27th Session. Transcript., 1967 (Box 4, Folder 5)
- Convention 27th Session. Transcript., 1967 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  July 13 1967. Pages 611 - 857. Copy 2.
- Convention 27th Session. Transcript., 1967 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  July 14 1967. Pages 858 - 1154. Copy 2.
- Convention 27th Session. Transcript., 1967 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  July 15 1967. Pages 1155 - 1361. Copy 2.
- Convention 27th Session. Booklets., 1967 (Box 4, Folder 9)
- Board of Directors. Minutes., 1947-1949 (Box 4, Folder 10)
- Board of Directors. Minutes., 1950-1954 (Box 4, Folder 11)
- Board of Directors. Minutes., 1968 (Box 4, Folder 12)
- 1916 Wabash Railroad Strike. Newspaper clippings. (Box 4, Folder 13)
- Proposed Agreement with SUNA, 1960 (Box 4, Folder 14)
- Electronic Yards Reports., 1961 (Box 4, Folder 15)
- Rules Negotiations. Newspaper Clippings and other Documents., 1962 (Box 4, Folder 16)
- Wage Movement., 1964 (Box 4, Folder 17)
- US Railroad Labor Board. Dockets No. 3048 and 3049. Transcript., 1922 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  December 20 1922.
- Supreme Court, Erie County, New York. Horace Parks vs. Switchmen's Union of North America., 1925 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  May 21 1925.
- US Railroad Labor Board. Docket No. 3044 and 3045., 1924 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  January 4 1924.
- US Court of Appeals. Docket No. 26739., 1960 (Box 4, Folder 21)
- Report of the Presidential Railroad Commission. Appendix 2., 1962 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  February 1962.
- Effect of Pay Structure Recommendations. Report., 1963 (Box 4, Folder 23)
- Special Board of Adjustment No. 696. SUNA vs. Buffalo Creek Railroad., 1966 (Box 4, Folder 24)
- Correspondence., 1910-1919 (Box 4, Folder 25)
- Correspondence, 1920-1923 (Box 4, Folder 26)
- Correspondence., 1937 (Box 4, Folder 27)
- Correspondence, 1943-1948 (Box 4, Folder 28)
- Correspondence., 1953-1957 (Box 4, Folder 29)
- Correspondence and the Senior Citizen News, 1963-1969 (Box 4, Folder 30)
- Membership, 1903-1967 (Box 4, Folder 31)
  January 1903 - December 1967
- Classes on Railroad Labor Relations. Correspondence., 1954-1955 (Box 4, Folder 32)
- Facts on Unification., 1967 (Box 4, Folder 33)
- Proceedings and References Manual for Vice Presidents, 1963 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  Folder 1 of 2
- Procedure and Reference Manual for Vice-Presidents, 1963 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  Folder 2 of 2
- Brotherhood of Railway Trainmen and SUNA. Workbook., 1968 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  Folder 1 of 3.
- Workbook. UTU. Hot Springs, Arkansas., 1968 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  Folder 2 of 3
- Workbook. UTU. Hot Springs, Arkansas., 1968 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  Folder 3 of 3.
- ORB and B. Brotherhood of Railway Trainmen. Unification Agreement. (Box 5, Folder 6)
  No date.
- Unification and Constitution Convention. Minutes., 1968 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  May 6 - 20 1968. Days 1 - 10.
- Unification and Constitution Convention. Minutes., 1968 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  May 21 - June 5 1968. Days 11 - 22.
- Unification and Constitution Convention. Minutes., 1968 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  June 7 - 22 1968. Days 23 - 33.
- Unification and Constitution Convention. Minutes., 1968 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  June 28 - August 5 1968. Days 34 - 45.
- Unification and Constitution Convention. Minutes., 1968 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  August 6 - 16 1968. Days 46 - 54.
- Unification and Constitution Convention. Foreman Committees Proposed Agreement., 1968 (Box 5, Folder 12)
- Unification and Constitution Convention. Signed Agreement., 1968 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  Folder 1 of 2. August 16 1968.
- Unification and Constitution Convention. Signed Agreement., 1968 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  Folder 2 of 2. August 16 1968.
- Unification and Constitution Convention. Index to Minutes., 1968 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  Folder 1 of 2.
- Unification and Constitution Convention. Index to minutes., 1968 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  Folder 2 of 2.
- The Switchmen's Light., 1961-1963 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  November 1961 - November 1963.
- The Switchmen's Light., 1964 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  Volume 1 Numbers 1 - 6.
- The Switchmen's Light., 1965 (Box 5, Folder 19)
- The Switchmen's Light., 1966-1967 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  December 1966 - June 1967.
- The Switchmen's Light Correspondence., 1963-1967 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  Drawings and letters.
- Railroad Carrier Mergers. Anti-Trust Hearings., 1962 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  Court documents and correspondence.
- The International Board of Directors. Minute book., 1959-1963 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  June 1959 - June 1963. Bound book.
- International Board of Directors. Minute book., 1963-1967 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  July 1963 - July 1967. Bound book.
- International Board of Directors. Minute book., 1967-1971 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  July 1967 - July 1971. Bound book.
- Executive Session Minutes., 1965-1968 (Box 6, Folder 5)
- Guide for Negotiating Agreements. (Box 6, Folder 6)
  2 booklets. No date.
- Agreements., 1908-1949 (Box 6, Folder 7)
- Agreements, 1950-1955 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  12 booklets
- Agreements, 1956 (Box 6, Folder 9)
- Agreements, 1958-1960 (Box 6, Folder 10)
- Agreements, 1964-1969 (Box 6, Folder 11)
- Group Disability Benefits. (Box 6, Folder 12)
- Rules and Wage Schedules, 1902-1908 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  14 booklets.
- Wage Schedules and Regulations, 1910-1919 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  22 booklets
- Rules and Wage Schedules, 1920-1923 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  13 booklets
- Rules and Wage Schedules, 1924 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  21 booklets
- Wage Schedules and Rules, 1926-1929 (Box 6, Folder 17)
- Wage Schedules and Rules, 1930-1939 (Box 6, Folder 18)
- Wage Schedules, 1942-1943 (Box 7, Folder 1)
- Schedule of Pay and Regulations, 1944 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  13 booklets.
- Wage Schedules and Rules, 1945-1948 (Box 7, Folder 3)
- Wage Schedules, 1949 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  11 booklets
- Rules and Wage Schedules, 1950 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  9 booklets.
- Rules and Rates of Pay, 1951-1955 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  5 booklets
- Schedule of Pay and Regulations, 1956 (Box 7, Folder 7)
- Wage Schedules and Rules, 1957 (Box 7, Folder 8)
- Wage Schedules, 1960-1963 (Box 7, Folder 9)
- Wage Schedules, 1964-1968 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  8 booklets
- Wage Schedules (Box 7, Folder 11)
  No date. 2 booklets.
- Rule Books, 1906-1939 (Box 7, Folder 12)
- Rule Books, 1943-1969 (Box 7, Folder 13)
- Member Feedback on Proposed Merger. Against. Locals 1-124., 1966 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  Postcards
- Member Feedback on Proposed Merger. Against. Locals 128-198., 1966 (Box 7, Folder 15)
- Member Feedback on Proposed Merger. Against. Locals 213-390., 1966 (Box 7, Folder 16)
- Member Feedback on Proposed Merger. Against. Locals 412-460., 1966 (Box 7, Folder 17)
- Member Feedback on Proposed Merger. For. Locals 1-39., 1966 (Box 7, Folder 18)
- Member Feedback on Proposed Merger. For. Locals 45-114., 1966 (Box 7, Folder 19)
- Member Feedback on Proposed Merger. For. Locals 120-157., 1966 (Box 7, Folder 20)
- Member Feedback on Proposed Merger. For. Locals 158-199., 1966 (Box 7, Folder 21)
  Postcards.
- Member Feedback on Proposed Merger. For. Locals 200-261., 1966 (Box 7, Folder 22)
- Member Feedback on Proposed Merger. For. Locals 262-317., 1966 (Box 7, Folder 23)
- Member Feedback on Proposed Merger. For. Locals 329-460., 1966 (Box 7, Folder 24)